# Fraser Macallum

fmacallum@shaw.ca
linkedin.com/in/fraser-macallum-752b2716b
Portfolio:
https://www.fmacal.com/

As a Computer Science diploma graduate, I have obtained skills in system analysis and development for practical IT solutions. I worked in a team that delivered a WordPress plugin and wrote effective technical documentation. I have experience as a computer technology lab technologist and part time instructor at a post-secondary institution where I tutored students and helped prepare computer lab environments.

## **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Java, Python

Source Control: Git, GitHub Frameworks: Node JS, Express JS, React

**Libraries:** Sequelize JS, Mongoose, jQuery, Socket IO, Axios **Technologies:** Docker, Portainer, Traefik, Amazon AWS

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Postman, Unity, Wireshark, Hyper-V

Administration: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu), Windows Server

Database: MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle 11g

**Soft Skills:** Technical Writing, team supervising, Agile development, tutoring, project sponsor

# **Experience**

MAY 2023 - CURRENT

# Lab Technologist II / Camosun College

- Modified and maintained computer hardware, software, and related network services in computer laboratories.
- Analyzed, designed, documented, developed, and tested computer software and hardware for courses and departmental operations.
- Tested apparatus using debugging tools, and constructed lab apparatus.

APRIL 2021 - CURRENT

## Lab Assistant, Technologies / Camosun College

- Helped students with basic questions and demonstrated the use of specialized software and equipment/tools.
- Assisted students in troubleshooting programming complexities and other discipline-specific lab tasks.
- Set up computer labs by preparing equipment and software.
- Researched and implemented new technologies for use in lab environments.
- Maintained a Docker Swarm platform that hosted several department services.

APRIL 2022 – JUNE 2022

# **Instructor, Part time / Camosun College**

- Taught a 7-week computer literacy course (COMP152).
- Delivered weekly lectures and provided support during lab sessions.
- Evaluated student submissions and provided feedback.

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

# **Developer and Technical Writer / Three Trees Calendar Camosun Capstone Project**

- Worked in an Agile team of three students to develop a WordPress calendar and course manager for non-profit organizations.
- Created a fast and asynchronous Node JS Express REST API using ES6 and Sequelize JS ORM.
- Wrote detailed technical documentation, including a project charter, team bios, user manual, and final report.
- Sponsored by Victoria-based companies Three Trees Technical and Oculus Design
- Project URL: http://capstone.camosun.ca/archived-capstone/June2020/public/TeamPages/Team%20Three%20Trees.php

JULY 2006 - NOVEMBER 2020

# Kitchen Supervisor / The Old Spaghetti Factory, Victoria BC

- Worked in a fast-paced restaurant environment.
- Led a kitchen crew to complete food preparation tasks as fast as possible to save labor costs.
- Ordered food items from suppliers.

## Education

### AUGUST 2020

# Information and Computer Systems Diploma / Camosun College, Victoria BC, 8.6 GPA

- Two-year, double-credentialed program that emphasizes the analysis and development of practical IT solutions
- Gained knowledge to:
  - o Program, deploy, secure, and maintain software applications to meet requirements
  - o Design, analyze, maintain, and interpret data
  - o Apply knowledge of basic project management skills to information technology activities
  - o Effectively communicate and collaborate with colleagues, team members, employers, and technical and non-technical personnel

### APRIL 2016

# **Associate of Arts Degree / Camosun College, Victoria BC**

- Two-year academic program made up 20 university-level courses composed mainly of English and social science classes
- Took Business Information Technology which introduced information systems in a business context